CURRICULUM VITAE

Personal Details:

Name: Tom Pierce

Date of Birth: 6th October 2004

Address: 85 Lindsay Road, Glasnevin, Dublin 9

Nationality: Irish

Languages spoken: English (native)

French (fluent)

Phone Number: 0894787346

Email: tompierce4@gmail.com

Portfolio: <u>tom-pierce.me</u>

Personal Statement:

Personable and friendly individual with excellent communication skills. Very good work ethic proven during my prior work in other jobs. I have good leadership and problem solving skills with the ability to work as a part of a team or on my own. Loyal, trustworthy and conscientious with excellent time keeping skills and a flexible attitude.

I moved to France with my family in 2007 where we lived for 3 years in the French countryside. I began school while there, at the time speaking no french when I started. I adapted quickly and soon learnt the language while in school and on a day to day basis with my friends. It was a fantastic experience for my family and I, one which we thoroughly enjoyed. We then moved back to Ireland when I was 6 years old and I had to quickly re-adapt to living in Ireland again. I believe this really illustrates my ability to quickly learn and adapt to new environments

Education:

Secondary:

Ardscoil Rís Secondary School, Griffith Avenue, Dublin 09. (2017-2022)

Primary:

Lindsay Road National School, Lindsay Road, Glasnevin, Dublin 09. (2010-2017)

École de Maternelle, La Motte-en-Bauges, 73340, France. (2007-2010)

Experience:

The Odin Project

June 2023 - Present

I decided to teach myself web development through The Odin Project curriculum. Web development and software engineering is something I have always been interested in.

RS Ireland

September 2022- June 2023

Glenview Industrial Estate, Herberton Road

- Started at the trade counter with very little experience in any of the products.
- Quickly settled into the role and became familiar with the roles as well as with the problem solving aspect of the job.
- Earned a promotion to join the technical department in assisting customers with any product queries they had.

Le Petit Breton

June 2021 - January 2022

1A Drumcondra Rd Lower, Botanic, Dublin 9

- Started as a KP but then quickly became a waiter.
- Lots of experience as a waiter with customers and taking orders.

CaterWaiter

August 2022

Straffan Rd, Moneycooly, Maynooth, Co. Kildare

- Worked as a waiter on multiple occasions
- Worked silver service at the horse show in the RDS, working five 13 hour shifts

Small Changes Wholefoods

April 2019 - July 2019

Small Changes, 40 Drumcondra Rd Lower, Drumcondra, Dublin 09

Cleaning in the shop as well as closing up the shop in the evening.

Coding Tutor

Sep 2019 - March 2020

The Croke Park CoderDojo, Dublin 9

Assisting the instructor teaching coding to primary and secondary school children.

Projects:

ZipLink

ZipLink is a url shortening web app that I created as my first project on my own. I developed the backend API and frontend client. It is built using React, ExpressJS and MongoDB as a database. ziplink.xyz

StockTracker:

StockTracker is a web app to help keep track of your positions in the stock market. With a user-friendly UI it is easy to pick up and start using. stocktracker.co

Greed Solver:

Greed is a game created by Noel Friedrich, I recreated the game in python cli and also a "solver" that traverses all possible routes and returns the highest scoring route. The project can be found at https://github.com/Tom-Pierce/greed-solver